Guide to the Adam Reynolds Photographs, 2013-2015 RL.11290
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Adam Reynolds photographs
2013-2015
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Reynolds, Adam
RL.11290
2.0 Linear Feet
Adam Reynolds is a conceptual documentary photographer whose work explores contemporary political conflict, primarily in the Middle East. His series "Architecture of an Existential Threat" was the 2016 winner of the ADA Collection Award for an Emerging Documentarian. Taken in Israel between 2013 and 2015, the photographs document bomb shelters and sealable rooms to which residents of the State of Israel are required to have access. There are over 10,000 of these public and private bomb shelters in Israel and the Occupied Territories. The photographs show the way these spaces are normalized in Israeli life, using them as community centers, places of worship, or bars. Reynolds writes that "these shelters are the architecture of an existential threat--both real and perceived."
Biographical / Historical
Adam Reynolds is a conceptual documentary photographer whose work explores contemporary political conflict, primarily in the Middle East. He holds a Masters of Fine Art degree in photography from Indiana University. Adam holds undergraduate degrees in journalism and political science from Indiana University with a focus in photojournalism and Middle Eastern politics. He also holds a Masters degree in Islamic and Middle East Studies from Hebrew University in Jerusalem.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Adam Reynolds Photographs were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2016.
Scope and Contents
Adam Reynolds's series "Architecture of an Existential Threat" was the 2016 winner of the ADA Collection Award for an Emerging Documentarian. He included the following abstract of his work:
"Since its creation in 1948, the State of Israel has felt itself isolated and beset by enemies seeking its destruction. This collective siege mentality is best expressed in the ubiquity of the thousands of bomb shelters found throughout the country. By law all Israelis are required to have access to a bomb shelter and rooms that can be sealed off in case of an unconventional weapons attack. There are over 10,000 public and private bomb shelters found throughout Israel and the Occupied Territories.
The photographs in this series document these bomb shelters and offer a window into the collective mindset of the Israeli people. Israelis have normalized this “doomsday space” into their daily lives, often using the shelters as dance studios, community centers, pubs, and places of worship. For Jewish Israelis haunted by a history of exile and persecution, these shelters are the architecture of an existential threat – both real and perceived."
Archive of Documentary Arts (Duke University); Reynolds, Adam
- School bomb shelter, Ashkelon, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Donor plaques at the entrance of L'Chaim Holocaust Survivors Group Center/ public bomb shelter, Jerusalem, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Conference room/ bomb shelter at the Bible Lands Museum, Jerusalem, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Mosque/ bomb shelter at Hebrew University, Jerusalem, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Public bomb shelter at Ein Zivan, along the border with Syria in the occupied Golan Heights., 2015 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Student rec room/bomb shelter, University of Haifa, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Public bomb shelter beneath apartment complex, Jerusalem, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Public bomb shelter, Haifa, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Reinforced "safe area" conference room in the Knesset, Jerusalem, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Youth activity center/bomb shelter, Na’ale settlement in the occupied West Bank, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Home cosmetics studio inside of a ‘mamad’ safe-room, Gedera, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Youth activity center/public bomb shelter, Kiryat Shmona, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Pub/bomb shelter, Kibbutz Kfar Aza, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Employee bomb shelter inside the Tel Hai Industrial Park, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- A portrait of Baba Sali, an influential Moroccan rabbi, hangs at the entrance of a Sephardic Synagogue and Beit Midrash/bomb shelter, Eilat, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Bomb shelter inside of a primary school in the Druze village of Hurfeish in the Galilee, 2015 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Main train station in Sderot, built to withstand incoming rocket fire from Gaza, 2015 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Abandoned Israeli military bunker outside of Jericho in the occupied West Bank, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Door inside the municipal bomb shelter, Haifa, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Large concrete drainage tube repurposed as an ad hoc bomb shelter, Nitzan, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 2)